

D.O.B: 26/07/2000

in www.linkedin.com/in/samkey726

Contact Information

MOBILE: 07944994022 EMAIL: samkey726@gmail.com

Personal Statement

Adventurous and determined student with an expanding eagerness and willingness to make a substantial contribution within the workplace. At my finest when presented with a challenge, because of this I establish challenges in all aspects of my life- from participating as a course representative in my initial university year to learning three thoroughly different musical instruments. My time as course representative has presented me as a passionate individual, deriving from my enjoyment of communicating-whether it be comprised of intriguing debate or casual conversation.

Due to this I have also relished in team commanding roles from experience gained in instructing teams for university projects. For example, in my first year of studying I had to lead a team of developers working on a C++ version of the game Snake, this helped improve my ability to work towards deadlines and manage tasks between my team members. My time at Jet petrol station and Home Bargains has also improved my retail and customer service abilities, ensuring customers always want to return. Not only a capable team leader but a valuable team member who will strive to perform his best at any appointed task.

Qualifications & Education

Sheffield Hallam University: Sept 2021 - Present	
MSc Cyber Security	2.1 (est)
Sheffield Hallam University: Sept 2018 – June 2021	
BSc Honour Computer Science	2.2
John Leggott College: Sept 2016 – June 2018	
IT Diploma	D*
Extended IT Diploma	D*D*D*
A-Level Use of Mathematics	C
Additional Qualifications	
RSL Grade 4 Drum Performance	M
RSL Grade 3 Drum Performance	M

Skills & Hobbies

Computer & IT related

- Fluent in Object-Orientated programming and development, especially in the following languages:
 - o Java, C++, C#, JavaScript, Python, C
- Fluent with Event-Driven programming techniques and languages
- Excellent at web-development techniques and languages such as:
 - o HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ES6, PHP
- Fluent with several different Functional-Orientated programming methods and languages, such as:
 - Clojure, F#
- Knowledgeable with modern software development frameworks such as:
 - Vue.js, React, Electron, Express.js, .NET
- Fluent in many pieces of popular computer software including:
 - o Microsoft Office Suite, FileZilla, WinSCP, Audacity, Git, Unity, etc.
- Knowledge and experience of Linux based operating systems such as:
 - o Ubuntu-Server, Debian, Arch, etc.
- Experience with several relational & non-relational database solutions such as:
 - $\circ \qquad \text{Microsoft SQL Server, MongoDB, Oracle Database}$
- Great research ability, able to efficiently filter between useful and irrelevant information
- Excellent IT trouble-shooting skills

- Familiar with working within a terminal, be that Windows or Linux
- Great graphic editing and rendering skills utilizing software such as:
 - o Paint.NET, Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator

Networking

- Passion for servers and networking, leading to running my own Ubuntu-based home server with the following features:
 - o Built-in IPTABLES, advance security system, VPN, networking filtering/monitoring with PiHole.
- Experience with back-end networking applications such as Node.js
- · Knowledge and experience using different networking hardware present in modern company networks I.e:
 - o Switches, firewalls, etc.

Hardware

- Experience with microcontrollers such as the Raspberry Pi & Arduino
- Proficient at trouble-shooting PC hardware issues
- Strong fascination with computer construction leading to:
 - $\circ \qquad \text{Constructing many different PCs for different people} \\$
 - Creating quotes for several different PC builds

Social

- Excellent communication skills derived from years of operating within a team
- · Confident when team-speaking and managing a team, able to get a everyone striving for the same goal
- Extremely self-motivated, with a passion to continuously learn and improve
- Strong technical problem-solving abilities from years of computer programming and developing

Other

- Music has always been a strong passion, as a result I have obtained and continue to practice the following skills:
 - o Drumming (Obtaining RSL qualifications)
 - o Ability to play the Guitar

Work Experience

Clarks, August 2022 - Present

- Jubilee Way, DN15 6RB, Scunthorpe, Telephone: 01724 866462
- Working as a sales assistant. Working here greatly improved my ability to sell products through speaking with
 customers. It taught me how to drive better sale numbers through being charismatic, and listening to their needs
 and wants.

Home Bargains, December 2020 – June 2022

- Queens Rd, S2 4DR, Sheffield, Telephone: 0114 272 5709
- Working as a retail assistant. Working here allowed me to further develop my customer service and customer
 handling skills, ensuring to provide a respectable face for the company. My problem-solving was also improved as I
 was entrusted with selling proof-of-age items to the public.

Gulliver's Valley Resort, August 2020 – December 2020

- Mansfield Rd, S26 5QW Sheffield, Telephone: 01925 444888
- Working as a ride operator. Working here allowed me to improve my teamwork, team leading and problem-solving
 skills allowing me to work confidently within a team even during busy stress inducting times. As a rider operator this
 job involved a great amount of responsibility like ensuring the safety of ride guests, this trained me to pay close
 attention to my work.

Jet Petrol Station, August 2017 – August 2018

- Grange Ln S, Scunthorpe, Telephone: 01724 869973
- Working as a retail assistant. Working here allowed me to improve my customer service skills, making sure I provide
 the customer with the best shopping experience possible. I also went beyond helping customers with abstract
 problems such as: needing directions, giving advice on several types of cars, and making sure I can help whenever
 possible. From this job I am now able to work effectively in fast and high stress environments.

CRAM Computers, June 2015

- 190 Ashby Rd, Scunthorpe, Telephone: 01724 277259
- Working as an IT assistant. Working here involved fixing and trouble-shooting different PCs and computing
 equipment such as; printers, scanners, etc. This developed my customer service skills and problem-solving skills as I
 had to fix issues described by customers. I was able to fix PCs in an efficient and organized manner to ensure all the
 days jobs were completed.